It is the will of God for all of us to be set free from satanic bondage for the salvation of our souls.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua moves in the midst of the people ministering prayer,
the evil spirits tormenting them manifest violently
as they are cast out in the name above all names - Jesus Christ!
Let's watch as satan looses his grip on this man's life.
I made him kill himself.
I made him smoke.
I stole his money.
I stole his family.
He is addicted to drugs.
He is addicted to alcohol.
Who are you in this body?
I'm going to make him kill himself.
Who are you?
I am death.
How did you enter him?
I came in the air.
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Emmanuel, people of God!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Thoriso Maduna.
I am from Johannesburg, South Africa.
I came to The SCOAN in search of peace and deliverance,
to find and meet Jesus Christ and to see the face of God.
I started doing drugs when I was young.
Just before you tell us how the story began,
tell us what the things were that you were actually addicted to,
that brought you to The SCOAN.
Alcohol, cigarettes, drugs, women, pornography and a bad reputation.
I was addicted to hatred - just anything negative that any young man would experience in their life.
I was addicted to all negativity in a young man's life which only brings death.
Okay, tell us how it all started.
It started when I was 13 years old and it started through music.
The influence of the music that we were listening to at that time led us to...
When I say us, I mean I and my friends, but to make it more personal:
It led me to start drinking, smoking marijuana and cigarettes at a very young age.
It led us to become popular in our community as 'the bad boys'.
In order to maintain this popularity, one had to increase the rate of smoking and drinking -
to such a point where I would smoke 20-30 cigarettes a day, I would drink a bottle of rum daily.
It led us to using hard drugs - we moved on towards using cocaine and cardiamin.
I was addicted to the fast life of going to clubs from Thursday to Monday.
There was a club that I used to go to every day of the week without fail.
The amount of money it cost to maintain this life was honestly not manageable.
I lost my job, I lost my contracts, I lost everything in my life.
The only thing that I could say I had was my life.
I then started with criminal activities in order to maintain this lifestyle -
in order to maintain the alcohol, women and addiction to drugs.
Thoriso Maduna - Deliverance Testimony
We can understand exactly what our brother is talking about.
Right from the age of 13, you had these serious addictions.
Now we want you to be a little more specific, especially on this issue of drug addiction.
It is a problem that so many people around the world are facing especially young people.
Tell us - how did you start getting into this addiction to drugs
and what happened to your life once you began taking these drugs?
How serious was this addiction?
The impact is very painful
and I am sure that people with the same addiction worldwide will relate to it.
The impact that it had on my life is that I lost everything.
I lost my family, I lost myself, I lost God, I lost everything.
To such a point where these drugs take you over
and they make you believe that you don't have a problem.
They make you believe that you are the victim
when in actual fact, that is not the truth.
What they do is that they physically damage your brain
such that an individual cannot make any kind of advantageous decision for himself.
The impact now is that an individual - like what happened to me - starts to hate himself and the world.
You come to believe that the world hates you and everybody is against you.
You find yourself in a victim position.
The only result that comes from that is death
because if you don't kill yourself out of depression,
which comes as an effect of the drugs,
you intentionally put yourself in a situation
where you get killed either in a car accident because of intoxication,
in a fight where guns are being pulled out,
or through some other means or way.
What happened to me is that I found myself very close to death.
The Spirit of the living God throughout my trials at that time
has always been present, even when I was sinning.
There was a month I escaped three bad car accidents.
I was hijacked twice and
none of the bullets which were shot at me actually hit my body by the grace of God.
By the time I realised that I was very close to losing my life, I had given up.
The impact of the drugs on my mind was that I felt I needed protection
and I made arrangements to get a gun.
I got myself a gun but I couldn't find any bullets for the gun, by the grace of God.
I believed that I needed to protect myself, while in the actual fact the spirit was lying to me -
that gun was for me to kill myself.
So you are saying, brother, that under the influence of these drugs
you actually bought a gun and your intention was to take that gun and kill yourself?
That was the indirect intention.
The lie which came to me as a result of all these addictions was protection for myself.
But looking back today, I can confirm without a doubt
that the purchase of that gun was for suicide.
We can understand once again the severity of the addiction our brother is talking about.
Can you explain to us - was it something you were taking on a daily basis?
To maintain sanity, it had to be on a daily basis.
A bottle of rum, some drugs and two packets of cigarettes,
just so that one can stay sane and being normal on a daily basis.
You said, you began taking cocaine, which is a very hard drug.
What did that then graduate to after the cocaine? What drug did you then go to?
Because of the high cost of cocaine, I had to meddle down.
I then started with cardiamin, which is a cheaper version of cocaine.
That is one of the most vicious of the drugs which are out there and it is an international epidemic.
What it does is that it reconfigures your entire thought process mechanism,
in such a way that it blinds you completely.
Your brain cannot function under this drug whatsoever.
It changes your thoughts, it changes how you even look physically -
only to those who know you.
This drug can make you believe that the sky is red, even when the sky is blue.
It takes away the life source that is in you
such that it causes someone to have that deep hatred - not only for the world but also for himself.
It is only by the grace of God that one can get out of it.
I have got so many cases and examples of churches that I went to.
Before getting to that area, brother, tell us - for how many years were you addicted to these drugs?
From the time I was 13. I would say for approximately 18 years.
We can just Imagine what our brother is talking about. For 18 years he had this severe drug addiction.
You said that it came to a point where to finance this addiction, you had to go into crime.
Can you just explain what that spirit pushed you into doing to try and get money
to be able to maintain this addiction.
Under the control of these drugs, you lose your sense of heart,
and you would be willing to do anything.
It led me to partake in a few criminal activities which would augment my financial position
so that I could continue purchasing alcohol and drugs
and maintain that lifestyle which honestly leads to death.
All the good things I tried to do all failed.
Whether it was employment, business opportunities that could change the face of the country,
or community activities - they all failed.
But anything I touched that was bad, I succeeded, I flourished.
I was very well known and popular for being a 'bad boy'.
Maintaining that 'bad boy' image and status, you end up in a position where you sell your soul.
Where people get injured and people have to get hurt,
just for you to keep up with the spirit of that addiction.
You mentioned at the beginning that apart from drugs and alcohol,
this also gave you the spirit of lust, addiction to women and pornography.
Can you explain more about this as well.
Intoxication and the love for women go hand in hand.
It is like coffee and sugar - coffee, sugar and milk.
Whenever one gets addicted to intoxication of any form,
it brings on a spirit of lust -
both to the actual women, to pornography and things like that.
So I found myself having to go to strip clubs, just to keep up.
One does not have control of oneself, under any form whatsoever.
It is as though I was under mind control.
I didn't want to go to strip clubs but I couldn't help it.
I had no power, I had no ability to shake it off.
I had no ability to stand and say, "No, I am not going to do such".
I was under pure mind control and it was like living in a prison
where you could still see the light but you couldn't go towards the light.
You are in bondage, you are in chains and yet you can still see the freedom,
which is so much more painful than when you are in bondage and can't see what freedom is.
We can really understand from our brother what this pushed him to do.
Now brother, can you explain - had you ever before attempted to try and stop
taking these drugs and alcohol and what happened?
For many years, over a period of about five years, I have been on a quest
to get out of this life, to no avail whatsoever.
I have been to churches all over the country back at home in South Africa -
all to no avail.
This spirit was so powerful that when I prayed,
I would hear at the back of my mind something laughing at me.
Whenever pastors came and laid their hands on me, I would hear the spirit rebuking them.
It was so difficult to find deliverance especially back at home in South Africa
because it is given that deliverance comes at a price,
deliverance comes at a cost.
To give a practical example:
I would go to some churches and when it was offering time and I didn't have money at that point,
I couldn't really shout "Amen" as loud as I would like to shout "Amen".
But when I did have a lot of money, I would give a sizeable offering
and I would then feel confident enough to shout "Amen".
It made me to believe that deliverance comes at a cost.
Without actally awarding the pastor with a sizable offering or tithe, deliverance would not be possible.
Every single time I prayed and asked God for deliverance,
it wasn't a pure prayer because the prayer was based on money.
What I found here at The SCOAN was the freedom that comes with deliverance,
the peace that comes with deliverance and the ability to stand and have a clear and open mind,
to know myself and know that Christ is real, Jesus is real, He lives, He exists.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Brother, we still want you to come back to that point of your experience when you came here
but just before then, we want you to be a little bit more specific.
When you mentioned that some of the criminal activities you went into to try and fuel this drug addiction
by getting money. Just give an example of some of them that this spirit pushed you into
as an opportunity for other people to learn.
I engaged in quite a lot of fraudulent activities.
I am a relatively well connected individual back home.
We could foster some fraudulent activities,
which really gave us a lot of money like bank card schemes,
governmental contract schemes and so forth.
Car hijacking as well to which, funny enough, I also became a victim of.
It would provide quite a lot of money to an extent of about 30,000-40,000 rand a day.
But you wasted all that money on drugs?
Entertainment, intoxication, addiction, women and maintaining a bad reputation.
You talked about how you have been to so many places seeking for deliverance.
How did you actually come to hear about The SCOAN?
A relative of mine had come here a few years ago
in order to find deliverance for my brother who had cancer.
Unfortunately, my brother was in such a bad state that he couldn't come to The SCOAN.
A family representative had to come and she also got delivered upon coming here.
When she went back home, my brother was healed from cancer.
He was lying in bed...
Thoriso Maduna - Deliverance Testimony
He was lying in bed and the doctors had told us there was no more hope.
The hospice had also told us that there was no more hope.
All they did was that they gave him tablets for him to die in peace.
By God's grace, in a week he was up and he was even driving my car.
That was after a family member came to the SCOAN and
returned and ministered the Morning Water to your brother?
Yes! That is correct.
If I remember correctly, she didn't even have to minister to him, her presence healed him,
when she came directly from The SCOAN.
Unfortunately at that time, I wasn't seeing myself as one to go to church.
You know bad boys don't go to church.
We don't do those kind of things. Cool guys remain in the bars,
cool guys remain with women. We don't go to church.
At that time, I was just grateful for my brother's life.
I was not bothered about how it came about. I did not care at all.
A few months ago, my dad reminded me of the miracle that happened to my brother.
He said to me, "Thoriso Maduna, I think you should go and visit The SCOAN".
God bless him for his wisdom because he knew how to talk.
Because if he had said to me that I have to go to The SCOAN, I wouldn't have come.
What he did is that he gave me a suggestion that maybe it could help me.
I thought to myself that all I was looking for was a solution,
I was looking for a way out because I had found out that there was a terrible spirit
behind everything I was doing and I was a mess.
When I came here to The SCOAN, I came with no expectation.
I came with no anticipation.
The only thing which I was looking for was answers and deliverance.
How it came about, I didn't mind.
From whom it came, how or what it really was, was not much of my concern.
All I was looking for was deliverance.
To my amazement, that deliverance came for free!
Thoriso Maduna - Deliverance Testimony
At the back of my mind, somehow I was thinking to myself
that since now I am about to get delivered, I need to start putting money aside
because I had thought that deliverance doesn't come for free.
There is no high-rated man of God that I have met ... there must be money involved.
Just to show that the Holy Spirit is present here.
It came for free and it came in such a way which I did not expect.
I thank the Holy Spirit for allowing me to be able to receive deliverance.
For all the people who came from far and wide,
I know how it is like to look for a solution
such that you move all the way from your own country to come here
and believe me, it has been the best decision of my life.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We want you to explain to us exactly what happened in the service last week.
You were just sitting down,
Prophet T.B. Joshua began moving in the midst of the people, and he came towards you.
Just describe to us what happened at that moment.
It was the most interesting experience.
I didn't know exactly what to expect. I can see myself over there.
I didn't know what to expect.
What happened was that,
as the man of God was laying hands on the people - I was seated in the back row -
as the man of God was approaching,
my spiritual eye opened and I saw myself getting ready for a fight.
Yet, I could see the man of God coming closer.
The closer the man of God came, the more I got ready for the fight.
Immediately he came and put his hand on me, I felt as though I was hit by a big hammer.
I felt no pain at all but that hammer hit me light out!
I don't know what happened, I have no idea or recollection of what is on the TV screen.
I don't know what happened.
I mean if I were to look, I wouldn't confirm that was me, I would deny it.
By the time I got up, I felt as though I just woke up from a deep slumber.
I felt alive, I felt as though I had been sleeping for a long time,
I woke up from a deep sleep.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Thoriso Maduna - Deliverance Testimony
I wasn't conscious of anything that was happening around me.
I literally woke up from a deep sleep,
I saw the camera here, the light was on my face,
the evangelists were preaching and there was a lot of noise.
I was looking around and thinking to myself, "What is going on?
Where am I? How did I get here?"
And for the first time I could think clearly.
For the first time after a long time, I could hear myself reason and say,
"I am in The SCOAN and this is my deliverance, and this is me speaking".
Wow!
Just tell us, brother, ever since that deliverance last week,
it has been one week now - what has happened to your life?
Thoriso Maduna - Deliverance Testimony
I am not even going to talk about any cravings because there is no craving which exists.
Right now, it is an element which does not exist in my life.
It is as though it never existed in the past.
The cravings are no more, I don't know even know how it is like to crave anymore -
for drugs, alcohol, pornographic images, women, whatsoever.
I am free, in the name of Jesus!
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
You mean to say, brother, up to the point of your coming to The SCOAN
last week, you were still taking the drugs, alcohol, cigarettes?
It was only after your deliverance that you have stopped?
Yes! That is correct.
Even before I came, I somehow knew that it was the end.
I thought to myself, "Let me go out because it is going to be my last time".
But I found myself not having such a deep desire.
In fact, because I knew I was coming to The SCOAN,
I found myself wanting to read the Word more, so that I could understand a bit more where I am going.
Now, as you are standing here, it has been one week now.
You said before that this addiction literally controlled your life,
controlled your thinking, your reasoning faculties,
imprisoned you and blinded you from reality.
How are you reasoning, calculating and thinking right now?
I consider myself a super human.
My reasoning capacity has returned, I can think clearly, I can see clearly.
It's beautiful! It's beautiful for me to be myself again.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We know you are in a position to really give advice to people around the world,
especially those under the bondage of this kind of addiction.
We know around the world, it is such a serious problem -
people addicted to taking drugs, alcohol, smoking.
As someone that has passed through this addiction,
right now you are free from it and you are a living testimony.
What is your advice to people around the world,
especially young people who are still into this kind of addiction?
My advice is: I can understand and I know that you all want to be free.
The only way to get free is to know Jesus Christ.
There are no other means, there is no other way.
Pray hard and believe and find your genuine willingness to get deliverance
because the spirits of addiction and depression can only be taken away through deliverance.
There is no other way, there is no other mechanism that can assist.
My advice to everybody out there that is suffering from any kind of depression or addiction,
is to pray hard and have a genuine willingness to be delivered
and God will find you.
{Amen. Let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Finally, we know that there are many people who look at the lifestyle of people that are addicted,
maybe they envy them or are jealous of them,
they look at them and think they are living a high life, a good life.
As someone that was into such lifestyle and was part and parcel of that addiction
what would you like to tell such people?
I would like to tell those people:
Firstly, those who are into such a lifestyle - 'the bad boys' of the world -
I feel your pain, I know your pain, it is painful.
Get out of it, it is not worth it!
There is only death - that lifestyle will lead to your death.
There are only two ways where your life is positioned: It is either in Christ or in the grave.
All of us want to live - move towards Christ!
Move towards the Holy Spirit
and get out of that lifestyle as soon as you can.
Believe that you can do it, have a genuine willingness to find God and to be delivered
and God will find you.
To those who envy the guys who are popular and everything, pray for them!
That's all I can say - they need your prayers!
Instead of envying them, pray for them because it is a very painful place to be in.
Amen. Let's all put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We know the evidence of Jesus is lives changed
and we thank God for the transformation in our brother's life.
We believe his testimony will inspire many people around the world
to also seek deliverance in the name of Jesus Christ
and we believe we have learned many valuable lessons from his testimony.
We know that as you make the Word of God the standard for your life,
the best is yet to come in Jesus' name!
RV: Mel Flowers 25/03/2019